<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on About | Sergiu</title>
    <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on About | Sergiu</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:23:53 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal Technical Lead</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/the-ideal-technical-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/the-ideal-technical-lead/</guid>
      <description>Who wants to be a technical lead Becoming a technical lead is a great way to combine passion for technology with management skills, and it is important to understand what it entails. For experienced software developers who exhibit leadership skills and stay up to date on the latest technology, it may be beneficial to consider pursuing a technical lead position.
A technical lead needs to have a deep understanding of technology and software development practices, and should be personable and capable enough to effectively lead a team and collaborate with others 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compound effect and how to create an Investment Checklist</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/compund-effect-and-how-to-create-an-investment-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 12:45:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/compund-effect-and-how-to-create-an-investment-checklist/</guid>
      <description>The compound effect All good things in life come from #compounding, be it knowledge, health and even wealth! The compound effect meaning is exactly what it sounds like. As you may know from finance, compound interest can lead to surprisingly large returns. A penny that doubles in value each day for 31 days ends up being worth over $10 million.
Same concept is applied to Learning. Read something like even 5 pages a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Innovation and Efficiency Is Difficult</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/balancing-innovation-and-efficiency-is-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:15:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/balancing-innovation-and-efficiency-is-difficult/</guid>
      <description>How to balance being innovative and being efficient What happens to companies as they become more competent? When it comes to innovation inside large companies, the balance of power tips heavily toward improving their known and proven business model. They under-invest in the exploration of new value propositions and business models. More importantly, there’s a considerable lack of power when it comes to growth or transformative innovation.
Business leaders realize that the pace of competition has increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Edge Young Investors Have Is Time</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/the-greatest-edge-young-investors-have-is-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 21:29:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/the-greatest-edge-young-investors-have-is-time/</guid>
      <description>What are the main differences between trading and investing? After taking a two week break I&amp;rsquo;d like to recommend that you start your trading journey with a deep education on the financial markets and then read charts and watch price actions, building strategies based on your observations. Test these strategies with paper trading, while analyzing results and making continuous adjustments.
Investing takes a long-term approach to the markets and often applies to such purposes as retirement accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be a Trillionaire Crypto Crash</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-be-a-trillionaire-crypto-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 21:28:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-be-a-trillionaire-crypto-crash/</guid>
      <description>One bitcoin was worth $779 billions Late Tuesday afternoon, cryptocurrency pricing aggregation site CoinMarketCap.com, which is owned by Binance, self-dubbed &amp;ldquo;the world&amp;rsquo;s most trusted cryptocurrency data authority,&amp;quot; was hit with a shocking cyber failure or attack that artificially inflated individual crypto coins&#39; value 1.
 Figure 1: One bitcoin was worth $779 billions (Source: &#39;CoinMarketCap.com&#39;)  A system failure that artificially sent coin and token prices skyrocketing to valuations in the tens of billions of dollars per unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Resolved Its Outage 2021</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/aws-resolved-its-outage-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 21:51:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/aws-resolved-its-outage-2021/</guid>
      <description>The day the internet paused Amazon Web Services had one of its worst outages ever on Tuesday. The problems cascaded through the company’s retail operation—which uses software and apps that run on AWS—during the holiday shopping rush. Vans sat idle; drivers were sent home; packages piled up at the worst possible time 1.
Tuesday offered the kind of jolt that reminds us how many products and services are centralized in common data centers run by just a handful of big tech companies like Amazon, Microsoft and Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy National Day Romania 2021</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/happy-national-day-romania-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 20:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/happy-national-day-romania-2021/</guid>
      <description>Happy National Day, Romania! On 1st of December we celebrate Romania National Day which doubles as the day that commemorates the union of the separate ancient regions of Transylvania, Moldova, and Bukovina with the Romanian Kingdom to form present-day Romania and as the country’s Independence Day.
 Figure 1: Peles Castle (top-left), Rasnov Fortress (top-right), Black Sea resors (bottom-left), Danube Delta (bottom-right)  World Heritage Sites Romania is endowed with spectacular monasteries, thermal-spring spas, and charming villages set at the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Nuture a Digital Workforce</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-nuture-a-digital-workforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 21:07:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-nuture-a-digital-workforce/</guid>
      <description>Traditional organization structure follows a top-down management with ideas and strategy defined at the top then distributed to specialized teams that focus on specific technologies, processes, or resources.
Due to the hierarchical nature of a traditional organization structure, the individuals at the highest level of management may have little communication with employees who are not their direct subordinates. In many large global companies, growing organizational complexity, anchored in strong product, functional, and regional axes, has clouded accountabilities 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud as a Service Outlook 2025</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/cloud-as-a-service-outlook-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 18:56:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/cloud-as-a-service-outlook-2025/</guid>
      <description>Public cloud services market will see the fastest growth in spending, with a five-year CAGR of 21.3% To maintain strategic competitiveness, today’s CEOs and business leaders are focused on realizing growth and digital business change. Like so many things, the story starts with the pandemic, which forced companies to adopt a more technologically sophisticated approach to managing customer service.
This Traditional IT model was born out of ITIL and On-Premises based technology solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Next Cloud Evolution</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/serverless-next-cloud-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/serverless-next-cloud-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The next great evolution of cloud computing is known as Serverless. Digital transformation propels businesses and industries forward. Organizations of all sizes—from startups to global enterprises—focus on digital transformation not only to make scaled improvements, but also to drive significant change and fully embrace the digital age.
The pandemic has jump started and pushed many organizations into full gear to digitize their business models and transform with increased business agility, resiliency, and velocity, while driving new innovation and business values for the customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Wednesday First Post</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/writing-wednesday-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 15:17:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/writing-wednesday-first-post/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I wanted to start a blog. Anyone can write. All it takes is knowing a language and stringing words together. But learning to write well is a whole different story. Perhaps you’ve read a couple of books to improve your writing skills. And you’ve subscribed to the most popular blogs on writing.
I didn’t start the blog then, and figured that it’s not too late to start now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
