<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on About | Sergiu</title>
    <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on About | Sergiu</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 21:51:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Resolved Its Outage 2021</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/aws-resolved-its-outage-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 21:51:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/aws-resolved-its-outage-2021/</guid>
      <description>The day the internet paused Amazon Web Services had one of its worst outages ever on Tuesday. The problems cascaded through the company’s retail operation—which uses software and apps that run on AWS—during the holiday shopping rush. Vans sat idle; drivers were sent home; packages piled up at the worst possible time [1].
Tuesday offered the kind of jolt that reminds us how many products and services are centralized in common data centers run by just a handful of big tech companies like Amazon, Microsoft and Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy National Day Romania 2021</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/happy-national-day-romania-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 20:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/happy-national-day-romania-2021/</guid>
      <description>Happy National Day, Romania! On 1st of December we celebrate Romania National Day which doubles as the day that commemorates the union of the separate ancient regions of Transylvania, Moldova, and Bukovina with the Romanian Kingdom to form present-day Romania and as the country’s Independence Day.
 Figure 1: Peles Castle (top-left), Rasnov Fortress (top-right), Black Sea resors (bottom-left), Danube Delta (bottom-right)  World Heritage Sites Romania is endowed with spectacular monasteries, thermal-spring spas, and charming villages set at the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Nuture a Digital Workforce</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-nuture-a-digital-workforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 21:07:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/how-to-nuture-a-digital-workforce/</guid>
      <description>Traditional organization structure follows a top-down approach with ideas and strategy defined at the top then distributed to specialized teams that focus on specific technologies, processes, or resources.
Unfortunately, it’s easy to quickly lose sight of the larger business objectives as the tasks are delegated into more and more specialized teams. This creates a silo effect where working teams are insulated from sister teams, and isolated from the larger organization. The end result is that it generally takes far longer than expected to deliver a product and it often falls well short of the vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud as a Service Outlook 2025</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/cloud-as-a-service-outlook-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 18:56:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/cloud-as-a-service-outlook-2025/</guid>
      <description>Public cloud services market will see the fastest growth in spending, with a five-year CAGR of 21.3% To maintain strategic competitiveness, today’s CEOs and business leaders are focused on realizing growth and digital business change. Like so many things, the story starts with the pandemic, which forced companies to adopt a more technologically sophisticated approach to managing customer service.
This Traditional IT model was born out of ITIL and On-Premises based technology solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Next Cloud Evolution</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/serverless-next-cloud-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 16:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/serverless-next-cloud-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The next great evolution of cloud computing is known as Serverless. Digital transformation is what propels businesses and industries forward. Organizations of all sizes—from startups to global enterprises—focus on digital transformation not only to make scaled improvements, but also to drive significant change and fully embrace the digital age.
The pandemic has jump started and pushed many organizations into full gear to digitize their business models and transform with increased business agility, resiliency, and velocity, while driving new innovation and business values for the customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Wednesday First Post</title>
      <link>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/writing-wednesday-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 15:17:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sergiubodiu.github.io/sergiubodiu/posts/writing-wednesday-first-post/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I wanted to start a blog. Anyone can write. All it takes is knowing a language and stringing words together. But learning to write well is a whole different story. Perhaps you’ve read a couple of books to improve your writing skills. And you’ve subscribed to the most popular blogs on writing.
I didn’t start the blog then, and figured that it’s not too late to start now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
